a librivox recording all librivox recordings are in the public domain for
more information or To volunteer visit librivox.org this reading by J Hall the
Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum Chapter 6 The Cowardly Lion
All this time Dorothy and her companions had been walking through the thick woods.
The road was still paved with yellow brick, but these were much covered by
dried branches and dead leaves from the trees, and the walking was not at all
good. There were few birds in this part of the forest, for birds loved the open
country where there is plenty of sunshine. But now and then there came a
deep growl from some wild animal hidden among the trees. These sounds made the
little girl’s heart beat fast, for she did not know what made them; but Toto
knew, and he walked close to Dorothy’s side, and did not even bark in return. “How
long will it be,” the child asked of the Tin Woodman, “before we were out of the forest?”
“I cannot tell,” was the answer, “for I had never been to the Emerald City. But my
father went there once, when I was a boy, and he said it was a long journey
through a dangerous country, although nearer to the city where as dwells the
country is beautiful. But I am not afraid so long as I have my oil can and nothing
can hurt the Scarecrow, while you bear upon your forehead the mark of the Good
Witch’s kiss that will protect you from harm.” “But Toto!” said the girl anxiously.
“What will protect him?” “We must protect him ourselves if he is in danger,” replied
the Tin Woodman. Just as he spoke there came from the forest a terrible roar, and
the next moment a great Lion bounded into the road. With one blow of his paw
he sent the Scarecrow spinning over and over to the edge of the road, and then he
struck the Tin Woodman with his sharp claws. But, to the lion surprise,
he could make no impression on the 10 although the Woodman fell over in the
road and lay still.
Little Toto, now that he had an enemy to face, ran barking toward the Lion, and the
great beast had opened his mouth to bite the dog, when Dorothy, fearing Toto would
be killed, and heedless of danger, rushed forward and slept the Lion upon his nose
as hard as she could, while she cried out:
“Don’t you dare bite Toto! You ought to be ashamed of yourself, a big beast like you,
to bite a poor little dog!” “I didn’t bite
him,” said the Lion, as he rubbed his nose with his paw where Dorothy had hit it. “No,
but you tried to,” she retorted. “You were nothing but a big coward.” “I know it,” said
the Lion, hanging his head in shame.
“I’ve always known it. But how can I help
it?” “I don’t know, I’m sure. To think of your striking a stuffed man, like the
poor Scarecrow!” “Is he stuffed?” asked the Lion in surprise, as he watched her pick
up the Scarecrow and set him upon his feet, while she patted him into shape
again. “Of course he stuffed,” replied Dorothy, who was still angry. “That’s why
he went over so easily,” remarked the Lion.
“It astonished me to see him whirl around so. Is the other one stuffed also?” “No,” said
Dorothy, “he’s made of tin.” And she helped the Woodman up again.
“That’s why he nearly blunted my claws,” said the Lion. “When they scratched it
against the tent it made a cold shiver run down my back. What is that little
animal you are so tender of?” “He is my dog, Toto,” answered Dorothy. “Is he made of tin,
or stuffed?” asked the Lion. “Neither. He’s a
meat dog,” said the girl. “Oh! He’s a curious animal and seems remarkably small, now
that I look at it No one would think of biting such a little thing, except a
coward like me,” continued the Lion sadly.
“What makes you a coward?” asked Dorothy, looking at the great beast in wonder, for
he was as big as a small horse. “It’s a
mystery,” replied the Lion. “I suppose I was born that way. All the other animals in
the forest naturally expect me to be brave, for the Lion is every
thought to be the King of Beasts. I learned that if I roared very loudly
every living thing was frightened and got out of my way. Whenever I met a man
I’ve been awfully scared; but I just wore
it at him, and he has always run away as fast as he could If the elephants and
the tigers and the bears had ever tried to fight me, I should have run myself— —I’m
such a coward; but just as soon as they hear me roar
they all try to get away from me, and of
course I let them go.” “But that isn’t right. The King of Beasts shouldn’t be a
coward,” said the Scarecrow. “I know it,” returned the Lion, wiping a tear from his
eyes with the tip of his tail it's my great sorrow, and makes my life very
unhappy. But whenever there is danger, my heart begins to beat fast.” “Perhaps you
have heart disease,” said the Tin Woodman.
“It may be,” said the Lion. “If you have,” continued the Tin Woodman, “you ought to
be glad, for it proves you have a heart.
For my part, I have no heart; so I cannot have heart disease.” “Perhaps,” said the Lion
thoughtfully, “if I had no heart I should not be a coward.”
“Have you brains?” asked the Scarecrow.
“I suppose so. I’ve never looked to see,” replied the Lion. “I am going to the Great
Oz to ask him to give me some,” remarked the Scarecrow, “for my head is stuffed
with straw.” “And I'm going to ask him to give me a heart,” said the Woodman. “And I'm
going to ask him to sin Toto and me back to Kansas,” added Dorothy. “Do you think Oz
could give me courage?” asked the Cowardly Lion. “Just as easily as he could give me
brains,” said the Scarecrow. “Or give me a heart,” said the Tin Woodman. “Or send me
back to Kansas,” said Dorothy. “Then, if you don’t mind, I’ll go with you,” said the
Lion, “for my life is simply unbearable without a bit of courage.” “You will be
very welcome,” answered Dorothy where you will help to keep away the other wild
beasts. It seems to me that they must be more cowardly than you are if they allow
you to scare them so easily.” “They really are,” said the Lion, “but that
doesn’t make me any braver as long as I know myself to be a coward
I shall be unhappy.” So once more the little company set off upon the journey,
the Lion walking with stately strides at Dorothy’s side. Toto did not approve this
new comrade at first, for he could not forget how nearly he had been crushed
between the lines great jaws. But after a time he became more at ease, and
presently Toto and the Cowardly Lion had grown to be good friends. During the rest
of that day there were no other adventures to mar the peace of their
journey. Once, indeed, the Tin Woodman stepped upon a beetle that was crawling
along the road, and killed the poor little thing.
This made the Tin Woodman very unhappy, for he was always careful not to hurt
any living creature; and as he walked along he wept several tears of sorrow
and regret. These tears ran slowly down his face and over the hinges of his jaw,
and there they rusted. When Dorothy presently asked him a question the Tin
Woodman cannot open his mouth, for his jaws were tightly rusted together. He
became greatly frightened at this and made many motions to Dorothy to relieve
him, but she could not understand. The Lion was also puzzled to know what was
wrong. But the Scarecrow seized the oil can from Dorothy’s basket and oiled the
Woodman’s jaws, so that after a few moments he could talk as well as before.
“This will serve me a lesson he said to look where I step or if I should kill
another bug or beetle I should surely cry again, and crying rusts my jaws so
that I cannot speak.” Thereafter he walked very carefully, with his eyes on the road,
and when he saw a tiny ant rolling by he
would step over it, so as not to harm it.
The Tin Woodman knew very well he had no heart, and therefore he took great care
never to be cruel or unkind to anything.
“You people with hearts,” he said, “have something to guide you, and need never do
wrong; but I have no heart, and so I must
be very careful. When Oz gives me a heart of course I mean mind so much end of
chapter 6
you